<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[CRV Homes]]></title><description><![CDATA[CRV Homes]]></description><link>https://www.crvhomes.com/blog</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 04:27:34 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.crvhomes.com/blog-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Building a Home in Tanglewood]]></title><description><![CDATA[Overview Located just outside the 610 Loop in West Houston, Tanglewood is North of Bellaire and West of River Oaks. The neighborhood is...]]></description><link>https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-tanglewood</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6082d779fecb960016024f61</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 14:23:39 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/8231d7_2d6c5a15890c4550abbea8faf8c4ccda~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_623,h_414,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Daniel Cai</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><u>Overview</u></p>
<p>Located just outside the 610 Loop in West Houston, Tanglewood is North of Bellaire and West of River Oaks. The neighborhood is managed by the Tanglewood Homes Association and is known for its large, luxurious homes and upscale atmosphere. The beautiful homes around the neighborhood make it a pleasure to live in. The gorgeous scenery will captivate those just walking or driving around. In addition, its exceptional location allows the residents of Tanglewood to have easy access to many shopping, dining, and entertainment hotspots and a short commute to the other parts of Houston. Finally, the neighborhood has access to many of Houston’s best schools, which attracts many families to the neighborhood. The allure of the neighborhood causes many to fall in love with Tanglewood and either buy a home or build their own custom dream home in the neighborhood.</p>

<p><u>Location</u></p>
<p>Tanglewood features an ideal location due to its relatively central location. Residents of the neighborhood often have a short commute to work as main roads like Memorial Drive, Sane Felipe Street, Woodway Drive, and the 610 Loop connect the neighborhood to major job centers like Downtown, the Galleria, the Energy Corridor, and the Texas Medical Center. In addition, Tanglewood is just next to the 610 Loop, which shortens the commute when travelling to the other parts of Houston, which may be located further away. Because the neighborhood is not as large as other Houston neighborhoods, the quality of location will not vary much between homes like they would with homes in East End or Northside. The convenient location of Tanglewood definitely factors into why many choose this neighborhood to buy or build in.</p>

<p><u>Entertainment</u></p>
<p>Residents in Tanglewood also have a seemingly limitless number of options to choose from for entertainment. From dining to shopping to nightlife, Tanglewood has it all. In fact, just South of the neighborhood resides the Galleria, one of Houston’s largest malls. The Galleria is a popular location for a weekend outing as it features a vast number of stores that sell almost anything you can imagine from clothes to shoes to toys. However, Tanglewood also has many local, homegrown businesses that attract its residents like Paris Texas Apparel and many local restaurants like Adair Kitchen, Roegels Barbecue, and Dish Society. And there is never a boring moment as there are many more options to explore near the neighborhood. For those seeking an exciting nightlife, Tanglewood is also in close proximity to Belvedere, Table on Post Oak, and The Testing Room, which can be a fun night with friends. Living in Tanglewood allows its residents to access a myriad of entertainment options and have an exciting lifestyle.</p>

<p><u>Amenities</u></p>
<p>Tanglewood homeowners will have no shortage of opportunities to go outside and get sunshine as it is filled with many appealing parks and beautiful scenery. Tanglewood Park, Tanglewood Bark Park, Grady Park, and Memorial Park are all great places to visit or take your children. These parks allow for a variety of sports from tennis to soccer to baseball. In addition, they are children friendly as they feature playgrounds. Even just jogging or walking around the neighborhood can be a joy, as the gorgeous scenery of the neighborhood is one of its main attractions. Residents of Tanglewood have no shortage of opportunities to go outside and get some sunshine.</p>

<p><u>Schools</u></p>
<p>Any family considering a new neighborhood is going to look at the schools and educational opportunities provided by them. Tanglewood is no exception, and fortunately, it features some of Houston’s best schools. The public schools in the neighborhood include Briargrove Elementary Schools, Grade Middle School, and Lee High Schools. However, families are not limited by these options as they can opt out of these schools and look into other Houston schools. Other common options include Mandarin Immersion Magnet School, T.H. Rogers School, and Westside High School. For those looking into private schools, popular options include St. Johns School, The Kinkaid School, Strake Jesuit College Preparatory, and St. Agnes Academy. Schools are always a high priority for families and Tanglewood allows families a number of fantastic educational opportunities.</p>

<p><u>Conclusion</u></p>
<p>Homes in Tanglewood are in high demand and will likely continue to be because of its ideal location, vast number of entertainment options, great amenities, and fantastic schools. This amazing neighborhood combined with CRV Home’s experience building custom homes allows CRV Home’s homebuilding clients with everything they need to piece together their perfect life. While Tanglewood will not always suit everyone, Houston offers a diverse array of neighborhoods and my previous blog posts on <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-the-northside" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Northside</u></a>, <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-east-end" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>East End</u></a>, and <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-west-university-place" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>West University Place</u></a> are all great places to start looking for your ideal neighborhood. </p>

<p>CRV Homes can help you build your dream home in Tanglewood or any of Houston’s other amazing neighborhoods. Schedule your free idea session regarding custom homebuilding in Houston and get a free quote today by contacting CRV Homes. <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/start" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Click here</u></a> to get started.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Building a Home in the Northside]]></title><description><![CDATA[Overview Anyone looking to buy or build a home within the Houston area should at least consider North Side as it offers a peaceful,...]]></description><link>https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-the-northside</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6075f2eb389d35002bea54d9</guid><pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 19:39:45 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/8231d7_82d2463ccf394cfea0e7e2c5481da3c9~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_768,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Daniel Cai</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><u>Overview</u></p>
<p>Anyone looking to buy or build a home within the Houston area should at least consider North Side as it offers a peaceful, secluded family lifestyle while having reasonable commutes to many of Houston’s most popular business and entertainment centers. As the name suggests, Northside is North of Central/Downtown Houston and is a vast neighborhood as it starts right above Downtown Houston but expands far past the 610 Loop. While its size leads to many unique atmospheres depending on the exact area, this also means that Northside is diverse and offers many options to choose from depending on your own personal circumstances and home preferences. Overall, Northside provides multiple unique communities that attract many residents looking to buy or build a home.</p>

<p><u>Location</u></p>
<p>Northside’s large size results in the locations within the neighborhood to vary greatly; however, this also means that potential residents of the neighborhood can choose a location specific to their needs. On the southern edge of Northside, homeowners are only a short commute from downtown. This is perfect for anyone whose workplace is in the area and is looking for a short commute or for anyone seeking a more lively lifestyle. Further up north are more secluded neighborhoods that may prove attractive to those looking to start or raise a family or those who just want some space from the hustle and bustle of the city. However, just because these areas are further from Downtown Houston do not make them less attractive. Each part of the neighborhood provides a sense of a close knit community and each has many forms of unique entertainment options not found anywhere else in Houston. Northside’s great size allows those looking to buy or build a home to pick their ideal location that suits their needs.</p>

<p><u>Entertainment</u></p>
<p>There is no shortage of dining, shopping, and entertainment options perfect for a relaxing evening after work or an enjoyable weekend excursion in the Northside neighborhood. First, Northside offers plenty of local restaurants and cafes to visit. A few include Esther’s Signature Dish, GrindHouse, and Golden Seafood House. Northside also offers many shopping options. Just driving around, one can see many different plazas to explore, each with many unique stores to choose from. Additionally, if you live closer to the southern border of the neighborhood, many of Houston’s amazing entertainment hotspots become available with only a short commute. And those who live further north should not worry or feel left out because exploring the rest of Houston, like going to the Houston Zoo or visiting the Houston Rodeo at NRG Stadium, can be an exciting day trip. Living in the Northside neighborhood allows for many opportunities to go out and explore Houston.</p>

<p><u>Amenities</u></p>
<p>Northside also offers many amenities that allow for its residents to get plenty of sunshine. Additionally, residents have access to multiple local parks, such as Kerr Park, Northline Park, and Clark Park, which are perfect for those who enjoy the outdoors. These parks also allow for a variety of sports like football, soccer, or running. No matter where in Northside you are thinking about buying or building in, there will be no shortage of outdoor activity.</p>

<p><u>Schools</u></p>
<p>Those who have a family are, of course, going to look into the neighborhood's schools and try to offer their children the best educational opportunities possible. Northside has a large selection of schools that families can choose from. The public schools in the neighborhood are in the Houston Independent School District and include Burrus Elementary School, North Houston Early College High, and Northside High School. However, there are also many private and charter schools available such as St. Pius and YES Prep Northside Secondary School. Of course, there are many schools not on this list, but available to those who live in the neighborhood, and families should research their options to give their children the best education.</p>

<p><u>Conclusion</u></p>
<p>Homes in Northside are and will continue to be in high demand because it provides its residents a diverse lifestyle and culture and is home to many of Houston’s main attractions. The amazing neighborhood combined with CRV Home’s custom homes allows CRV Home’s homebuilding clients with everything they need to piece together their perfect life. While Northside will not always suit everyone, Houston offers a diverse array of neighborhoods and my previous blog posts on on <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-the-riverside-terrace" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Riverside Terrace</u></a>, the <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-the-memorial-villages" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Memorial Villages</u></a>, and<a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-braeswood-place" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u> Braeswood Place</u></a> are all great places to start looking for your ideal neighborhood. </p>

<p>CRV Homes can help you build your dream home in the Northside or any of Houston’s other amazing neighborhoods. Schedule your free idea session regarding custom homebuilding in Houston and get a free quote today by contacting CRV Homes. <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/start" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Click here</u></a> to get started.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Building a Home in East End]]></title><description><![CDATA[Overview As one of Houston’s largest neighborhoods, East End resides in Southeast Houston and extends from the Eastern edge of Downtown...]]></description><link>https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-east-end</link><guid isPermaLink="false">606dd2aa291b340015ef6df5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 15:49:22 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/8231d7_0f6507e638994dd29ed215bf6e0c5a20~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_576,h_432,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Daniel Cai</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><u>Overview</u></p>
<p>As one of Houston’s largest neighborhoods, East End resides in Southeast Houston and extends from the Eastern edge of Downtown Houston to the Southeast edge of Interstate 610. In addition, it is bounded by Clinton Drive in the North and Interstate 45 in the South. East End is home to many commercial and industrial districts, which makes the neighborhood all the more attractive to those who are looking for work and want a short commute to work. However, East End also provides many opportunities for entertainment. The vast size of this neighborhood creates a diverse culture, which leads to many murals and pieces of local artwork, a multitude of galleries, and many opportunities for live performance art and music. No matter your background, East End provides many unique communities that attract a variety of homebuyers and homebuilders.</p>

<p><u>Location</u></p>
<p>Due to East End’s large size, locations within the neighborhood can vary greatly, but this also means that you can find your ideal location specific to your needs. On the Northwestern edge of East End, you would be close to Houston’s Downtown and closer to other business centers in Western part of Houston, which is convenient if you work there. Since this location is closer to downtown, it may provide a more lively atmosphere when compared to other parts of the neighborhood. Just past the Western border of East End is the University of Houston, and this part of East End may prove attractive to college students who attend the University. Not only does it feature a short commute, but also would likely provide a community of college students. However, other parts of the neighborhood may provide a more peaceful and residential feeling perfect for those looking to settle down or for somewhere to raise their families. Due to its vast size, East End allows homebuyers and homebuilders to pick their ideal location that suits their needs.</p>

<p><u>Entertainment</u></p>
<p>Within East End, there is no shortage of dining, shopping, and entertainment options perfect for a relaxing evening after work or an enjoyable weekend excursion. East End seems to have an unlimited number of options for entertainment and will almost always have something for you, no matter what you are looking for. Firstly, East End features a vast number of amazing restaurants to try out. Ninfa’s, Andes Cafe, and Kanomwan Thai Restaurant are all popular dining options among East End residents.</p>
<p>In terms of shopping options, East End features many plazas and malls filled with many stores for clothes or other essentials including Harrisburg Plaza, Lawndale Shopping Center, and Gulf Gate Mall. But for smaller businesses local to East End, residents have the opportunity to visit local bakeries, meat markets, and farmers markets. Residents of East End have plenty of options for entertainment, making it one of Houston’s most attractive neighborhoods.</p>

<p><u>Amenities</u></p>
<p>East End homeowners will also have many opportunities for sunshine as the neighborhood is filled with parks. Eastwood Park, Forest Park, and Mason Park are all beautiful parts that allow for many outdoor activities like running, baseball, soccer, tennis, and other sports. Buffalo Bayou is also nearby and provides many opportunities for outdoor adventures, whether for yourself or your kids. Finally, East End also offers many hiking and biking trails to its residents. No matter where in East End you are thinking about buying or homebuilding in, there will be no shortage of outdoor activity.</p>

<p><u>Schools</u></p>
<p>Schools are always an important consideration of any family moving to a new neighborhood and East End is no exception. Public schools in the area are served by the Houston Independent School District (HISD) and include schools like Eastwood Academy and East Early College High School. However, residents also have the choice of sending their children to charter schools, which is a great alternative, and includes schools such as YES Prep East End Secondary, KIPP Explore Academy, and KIPP East End High School. All of these schools give families a wide array of educational opportunities to choose from when buying or homebuilding in the East End neighborhood.</p>

<p><u>Conclusion</u></p>
<p>Homes in East End are and will continue to be in high demand because it provides its residents a diverse lifestyle and culture and is home to many of Houston’s main attractions. The amazing neighborhood combined with CRV Home’s custom homes allows CRV Home’s homebuilding clients with everything they need to piece together their perfect life. While East End will not always suit everyone, Houston offers a diverse array of neighborhoods and my previous blog posts on <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-the-riverside-terrace" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Riverside Terrace</u></a>, the <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-the-memorial-villages" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Memorial Villages</u></a>, and<a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-braeswood-place" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u> Braeswood Place</u></a> are all great places to start looking for your ideal neighborhood. </p>

<p>CRV Homes can help you build your dream home in East End or any of Houston’s other amazing neighborhoods. Schedule your free idea session regarding custom homebuilding in Houston and get a free quote today by contacting CRV Homes. <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/start" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Click here</u></a> to get started.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Building a Home in Briargrove]]></title><description><![CDATA[Overview Residing in West Houston, Briargrove is one of Houston’s hottest and upcoming neighborhoods for residential real estate. The...]]></description><link>https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-briargrove</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60649ca0b449780015dbf434</guid><pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 16:03:18 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/8231d7_df9ba179da7b40038966cf9a1c17d1f8~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_600,h_400,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Daniel Cai</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><u>Overview</u></p>
<p>Residing in West Houston, Briargrove is one of Houston’s hottest and upcoming neighborhoods for residential real estate. The neighborhood is bounded by Woodway Drive in the north, Westheimer in the South, South Voss Road in the West, and Fountain View Drive in the East. While the neighborhood is smaller when compared to some of Houston’s other neighborhoods, it consists of almost exclusively residential homes and provides a lovely, serene atmosphere and small town feeling. Whether you are looking for land, looking to build a custom home, or looking to buy a home, Briargrove is definitely a neighborhood to look into.</p>

<p><u>Location</u></p>
<p>Briargrove’s location is ideal for those who want to have a peaceful lifestyle away from the busy city, while still remaining within close proximity to many of Houston’s prominent locations. The neighborhood features a short commute to various commercial buildings and retail districts. In addition, Briargrove is only a short drive from Downtown Houston and the Texas Medical Center.  And even if your destination is a little further out, Briargrove is also connected to many of Houston’s primary roads and highways such as Westheimer, San Felipe, and the 610 Loop, which allows for residents to have direct access to many other Houston neighborhoods that may be a little further out. Briargrove’s location allows for both convenience and serenity, which is a significant selling point of the neighborhood.</p>

<p><u>Entertainment</u></p>
<p>For those looking for dining, shopping, or entertainment options after a long day at work or for a fun weekend outing, Briargrove provides a seemingly unlimited number of options. For one, many commercial shopping centers, which feature dining, shopping, and more, are right next to the neighborhood. Briargrove Shopping Center,  Spectrum Shopping Center, and Briarcroft Shopping Center are all fantastic options. In addition, the Galleria, one of Houston’s largest malls, is only a short drive away and attracts a vast number of visitors from all around Houston. Finally, if these weren’t enough, residents can always visit central Houston. There, residents can visit the Museum district, look at exotic animals at the Houston Zoo, or go to Downtown Houston for more restaurants and stores.</p>

<p><u>Amenities</u></p>
<p>Briargrove has a homeowners association, called the Briargrove Property Owners Association, that maintains the atmosphere of the community by enforcing deed restrictions and architectural guidelines. In addition, they maintain the community’s common areas and provides numerous amenities, including a clubhouse and a pool. The neighborhood is also nearby the Houston Country Club for those who are interested. Finally, Briargrove is near many parks, both big and small, with the most prominent nearby park being Memorial Park, which features multiple trails, tennis courts, and more. Briargrove’s numerous amenities are an excellent bonus to anyone considering building in or moving to the neighborhood.</p>

<p><u>Schools</u></p>
<p>Since Briargrove is made up of mostly families, schools are an important consideration by many. Families in Briargrove have access to local public schools including Briar Grove Elementary, Mandarin Immersion Magnet School, T.H. Rogers School, and Memorial High School. In addition, families looking into private schools also have many great nearby options including the Kinkaid School and Episcopal High School. Briargrove features many diverse options for educational opportunities that attract many families to the neighborhood.</p>

<p><u>Conclusion</u></p>
<p>Homes in Briargrove are and will continue to be in high demand because it provides its residents a peaceful lifestyle with a small town feel while remaining close to many of Houston’s main attractions. The amazing neighborhood combined with CRV Home’s custom homes allows CRV Home’s homebuilding clients with everything they need to piece together their perfect life. However, if the Briargrove does not seem to be the right fit for you, Houston offers a diverse array of neighborhoods and my previous blog posts on <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-the-riverside-terrace" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Riverside Terrace</u></a>, the <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-the-memorial-villages" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Memorial Villages</u></a>, and <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-braeswood-place" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Braeswood Place</u></a> are all great places to start.</p>



<p>CRV Homes can help you build your dream home in Briargrove or any one of Houston’s other amazing neighborhoods. Schedule your free idea session regarding home building in Houston and get a free quote today by contacting CRV Homes. <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/start" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Click here</u></a> to get started.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Building a Home in the Riverside Terrace]]></title><description><![CDATA[Overview Located within Houston’s inner loop just under downtown Houston and surrounding Brays Bayou, Riverside Terrace is one of...]]></description><link>https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-the-riverside-terrace</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6048e46afa322a0015723151</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 15:30:31 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/8231d7_b19887e76f2f4bda9e4d9bec48e16961~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_670,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Daniel Cai</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><u>Overview</u></p>
<p>Located within Houston’s inner loop just under downtown Houston and surrounding Brays Bayou, Riverside Terrace is one of Houston’s most attractive residential neighborhoods. Historically, the neighborhood was home to many prominent families who built luxurious mansions, giving it a unique culture unlike most of Houston’s other neighborhoods. Today, the neighborhood’s reputation has not changed much as is known for its lavish homes, exceptional location, and many wonderful amenities. Home building in Riverside Terrace allows one to join this great neighborhood and fit right in while also living in their dream home.</p>

<p><u>Location</u></p>
<p>As Riverside Terrace sits within Houston’s inner loop, it is close to many of Houston’s business and entertainment centers. It is close to both Houston’s downtown and the Texas Medical Center, and getting to either location only requires a short drive. In addition, it’s location also grants easy access to the Houston Zoo and the Museum Districts, which are both enjoyable places to visit with friends or family. Since it’s near the center of Houston, no restaurant, store, or workplace would be too far of a drive. However, Riverside Terrace still maintains a peaceful and serene home life as it is somewhat removed from Houston’s hustle and bustle. </p>

<p><u>Amenities</u></p>
<p>Homes in Riverside Terrace also have many opportunities for sunshine and outdoor activities. As Riverside Terrace surrounds Brays Bayou, the bayou is a popular choice for runners, bikers, or those who are just looking for a relaxing afternoon stroll. A quick glance outside and one will realize the bountiful opportunities for outdoor activity. In addition, homes in Riverside Terrace have access to numerous parks such as Parkwood Park or MacGregor Park. Parks like Parkwood Park are a great place to take children on a weekend outdoor adventure while MacGregor Park is a great place for sporting activities such as tennis, swimming, or baseball. Weather one decides to home build or move to Riverside Terrace, there is no doubt they will be met with plenty of sunshine.</p>

<p><u>Schools</u></p>
<p>All families moving to a new location will be concerned with the schools in the area, and Riverside Terrace is no exception. Houston Independent School District serves homes in Riverside Terrace Spring Branch and grants students in the neighborhood with a great education. Most students attend Thompson Elementary School, Cullen Middle School, and Yates High School. However, since Riverside Terrace is a highly accessible location, students can apply for a variety of private or magnet schools, if the previously mentioned schools were not the right fit. Home building or buying in Riverside Terrace will provide students with many educational opportunities.</p>

<p><u>Conclusion</u></p>
<p>Riverside Terrace is and will likely continue to be one of Houston’s most in demand neighborhoods because of the vast amount of benefits it offers. From the exceptional location of the neighborhood to the remarkable amenities, Riverside Terrace is a popular neighborhood for many who are looking to build a home. This amazing neighborhood combined with CRV Home’s custom homes allows CRV Home’s home building clients to piece together their perfect life. However, if the Riverside Terrace does not seem to be the right fit, Houston offers a diverse array of neighborhoods and my previous blog posts on <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-the-memorial-villages" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Memorial Villages</u></a> and <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-braeswood-place" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Braeswood Place</u></a> are both great places to start. </p>

<p>CRV Homes can help you build your dream home in Riverside Terrace or any one of Houston’s other amazing neighborhoods. Schedule your free idea session regarding home building in Houston and get a free quote today by contacting CRV Homes. <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/start" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Click here</u></a> to get started.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Building a Home in the Memorial Villages]]></title><description><![CDATA[Overview Located East of River Oaks but West of Memorial itself, the Memorial Villages consist of six independent villages that include...]]></description><link>https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-the-memorial-villages</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6033b0bf33225d00173204de</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 13:36:45 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/8231d7_58384a54bd194ead9f041d121b329ac7~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_682,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Daniel Cai</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><u>Overview</u></p>
<p>Located East of River Oaks but West of Memorial itself, the Memorial Villages consist of six independent villages that include Hilshire Village, Piney Point Village, Spring Valley Village, Hedwig Village, Bunker Hill Village, and Hunters Creek Village. While located in Harris Country and often considered part of the Houston area, each village is actually its own autonomous municipal government and operates independent of Houston. This results in each village having its own mayor and city council members, and leads to a separate fire and police department for the villages. In addition, families living in the villages are zoned to schools in the Spring Branch Independent School District. Finally, since each village is its own municipality, each one has different challenging deed restrictions that can be difficult to navigate. However, these deed restrictions cause the villages to consist mainly of residential properties which allows for security, privacy, and a warming small town feeling. Overall, the Memorial Villages are a great place to live or build a home in as the villages have a great location, luxurious homes, amazing schools, and numerous entertainment hotspots.</p>

<p><u>Location</u></p>
<p>The location of the Memorial Villages is one of the primary reasons residents choose to live in the neighborhood. The neighborhood allows for a quick commute to Houston’s business centers such as Downtown Houston and the Texas Medical Center, which are both around 20 minutes by car. Additionally, the Memorial is next to many of Houston’s popular destinations such as Memorial Park and Memorial City Mall while also being within reasonable distance of attractions near Houston Downtown and Herman Park areas. And no matter where you want to go in Houston, The Memorial Villages allow for a reasonable commute, at worst.</p>

<p><u>Community</u></p>
<p>The Memorial Villages offer one of the most peaceful, walkable, and secure communities in Houston. This is largely due to the deed restrictions of the neighborhood that allow for only residential properties. This means that the Villages are free from the business of commercial properties, which have been pushed to the edges of the Villages. However, this means that the cities themselves are private, quiet, and a great place to live in while the restaurants and stores are still within walking distance or at most a short drive. It is no wonder that the Memorial Villages feature very low crime rates. Choosing CRV Home to build on your lot in Memorial Village allows clients to seamlessly navigate the unique deed restrictions and join the community the Villages have fostered.</p>

<p><u>Entertainment</u></p>
<p>While there aren’t any commercial properties within the Memorial Villages themselves due to deed restrictions, this does not mean you have to compromise if you decide to build a custom home in this neighborhood. There are still many vast and diverse options for shopping, dining, and nightlife just outside the Villages along its border. For starters, popular shopping destinations within a 10 minute drive include CityCentre, Memorial City Mall, and the Galleria. These shopping centers not only feature name brand stores but also support local businesses. In addition, a seemingly unlimited number of restaurants line the Villages including, but not limited to, A Moveable Feast, Bistro Provence, and RA Sushi. And in terms of nightlife, there are many exciting places to visit such as 24 Lounge, Memorial Wine Cellar, Monnalisa Bar. Finally, the Houston Country Club and Lakeside Country Club are both nearby for additional recreational and entertainment activities. While the Memorial Villages are out of the way of normal city life, this does not mean that you need to compromise in terms of entertainment and things to do.</p>

<p><u>Amenities</u></p>
<p>Memorial Park is one of the biggest parks in Houston and those who buy or build a home in the Memorial Villages will have easy access to it. The park always seems to be lively due to its multiple running/hiking trails, tennis courts, baseball field, swimming pool, and playgrounds. Additionally, Memorial Park is not the only park near the neighborhood as residents also have access to multiple others including Tanglewood Park, Bendwood Park, and Hedwig Park. In addition, the Saturday Farmers Market in the Villages, which is considered one of the best in Houston, also attracts numerous residents with fresh fruits and vegetables. Anyone living in the Villages will be sure to be met with plenty of sunshine.</p>

<p><u>Schools</u></p>
<p>Any family moving or building a home in a new neighborhood will be concerned with the schools in the area and the Villages are no exception. Schools in the Memorial Villages are handled by Spring Branch ISD and include some of the top ranked schools in the state. Spring Branch elementary schools include Rummel Creek Elementary and Frostwood Elementary, middle schools include Memorial Middle and Spring Branch Middle School, and high schools include Stratford High School and Memorial High School. In addition, the Memorial Villages are close to prominent private schools such as Duchesne Academy of the Sacred Heart and The Kinkaid School. Families in the Memorial Villages will find no shortage of great schools and educational opportunities.</p>

<p><u>Conclusion</u></p>
<p>Memorial Villages offers its residents everything from an amazing location to a private lifestyle with a small town feel. The amazing neighborhood combined with CRV Home’s custom homes allows CRV Home’s homebuilding clients with everything they need to piece together their perfect life. However, if the Memorial Villages do not seem to be the right fit for you, Houston offers a diverse array of neighborhoods and my previous blog posts on <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-montrose" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Montrose</u></a><u>, </u><a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-braeswood-place" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Braeswood Place</u></a><u>,</u> and <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-bellaire" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Bellaire</u></a> are both great places to start. </p>

<p>CRV Homes can help you build your dream home in Memorial Villages or any one of Houston’s other amazing neighborhoods. Schedule your free idea session regarding home building in Houston and get a free quote today by contacting CRV Homes. <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/start" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Click here</u></a> to get started.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Building a Home in Braeswood Place]]></title><description><![CDATA[Overview Southwest of Downtown Houston resides the Braeswood Place, which is roughly bounded by Holcombe Boulevard in the North,...]]></description><link>https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-braeswood-place</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60268f2204f1600017344af1</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 14:25:51 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/8231d7_13b6c435ff7246a08cbebff9799459d3~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_960,h_640,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Daniel Cai</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><u>Overview</u></p>
<p>Southwest of Downtown Houston resides the Braeswood Place, which is roughly bounded by Holcombe Boulevard in the North, Interstate 610 in the South, and Main Street in the East. Braeswood Place is a residential neighborhood that consists mostly of single family homes and comes with a unique set of benefits like no other neighborhood. The neighborhood is made up of around 2,200 homes and includes seven subdivisions. These subdivisions are Ayrshire, Braes Heights, Braes Oaks, Braes Manor, Braes Terrace, Emerald Forest, and Southern Oaks. If you are looking to build a custom home in Braeswood Place, CRV Homes can help you create your dream home that will make you fit right into the neighborhood.</p>

<p><u>Location</u></p>
<p>Braeswood Place has one of the best locations in Houston. While a small distance away from Houston’s center, this means it provides a peaceful, small town feeling while also having easy access to many of Houston’s most popular destinations. For example, Braeswood Place features a short commute to many of Houston’s business centers such as the Texas Medical Center and Houston Downtown. In addition, the neighborhood is close to many of Houston’s entertainment hotspots as explained later and allows for residents to easily go on a weekend outing. Braeswood Place’s location allows for a relatively short commute, no matter where you need to go.</p>

<p><u>Entertainment</u></p>
<p>The fact that homes in Braeswood Place have great accessibility to local entertainment hotspots is one of its main selling points. This includes Rice Village or the Galleria for a variety of dining and shopping options, NRG Stadium for sporting events and the rodeo, the Museum District or the Houston Zoo for a fun weekend excursion, and much more. Additionally, the neighborhood is close to many highly rated restaurants and a variety of different cuisines, so there is something for you no matter what you are craving. Braeswood Place’s combination of location, residential setting, and entertainment option is what attracts many of its residents and is one of the main reasons the neighborhood is in such high demand.</p>

<p><u>Amenities</u></p>
<p>Building a custom home in this neighborhood allows for access to multiple nearby parks that are within walking distance. Some popular examples include McGovern Park, Karl Young Park, and Linkwood Park. These parks let families partake in various outdoor sporting activities including baseball, soccer, or running. In addition families can easily go out for a nice walk or an exciting picnic. In addition, Braes Bayou, which runs horizontally through the neighborhood, is a popular choice for runners for their weekend run, bikers for their routes, and everyday residents for their afternoon stroll. Those who decide to live in Braeswood Place will be sure to get plenty of sunshine.</p>

<p><u>Schools</u></p>
<p>Families considering building or moving in Braeswood Place will have a variety of great schools to choose from. The public schools that homes in the neighborhood get zoned to include Mark Twain Elementary School, Henry Wadsworth Longfellow Elementary School, and Pershing Middle School. However, the neighborhood is also nearby many of Houston’s magnet schools that require students to apply to, but are easily reachable within a daily commute. Families looking into private schools should consider St. Vincent de Paul School and St. Marks Episcopal School as they are in close proximity, but many other private schools, such as St. Johns School and Episcopal High School, are easily accessible. Every family considers the schools of a neighborhood when moving or building and Braeswood Place offers many great options. If gaining access to better schools is a priority, looking into Braeswood Place may help you find the perfect home.</p>

<p><u>Conclusion</u></p>
<p>Braeswood Place offers its residents an amazing location to the vast amount of local amenities, Braeswood Place provides CRV Home’s homebuilding clients with everything they are looking for in a neighborhood. The amazing neighborhood combined with CRV Home’s custom homes allows people to piece together their perfect life.</p>

<p>If Braeswood Place does not seem to be the right fit for you, Houston offers a diverse array of neighborhoods. Previous blog posts on <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-montrose" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Montrose</u></a> and <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-bellaire" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Bellaire</u></a> are both great places to start.</p>

<p>CRV Homes can help you build your dream home in Braeswood Place or any one of Houston’s other amazing neighborhoods. To schedule your free idea session regarding home building in Houston and to get a free quote, contact CRV Homes today. <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/start" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Click here</u></a> to get started.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Building a Home in Montrose]]></title><description><![CDATA[Overview West of Downtown Houston and South of Buffalo Bayou resides the Montrose neighborhood, which is bounded by US 59 in the South,...]]></description><link>https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-montrose</link><guid isPermaLink="false">601b1e7808a55700175fa38d</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 22:10:17 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/8231d7_99ddd32d8c2d46cbbcd2fecb9ee60347~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_682,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Daniel Cai</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><u>Overview</u></p>
<p>West of Downtown Houston and South of Buffalo Bayou resides the Montrose neighborhood, which is bounded by US 59 in the South, Allen Parkway in the North, Shepard Drive in the West, and Taft Street in the East.</p>
<p>Montrose is a residential neighborhood with a unique set of benefits like no other. While just 7.5 square miles in size, this Houston neighborhood is defined by its unique culture, various entertainment hot spots, and diverse array of shopping and dining options. As such, residential properties in Montrose are in high demand, and CRV Homes can help you build your dream home that suits the Montrose area.</p>

<p><u>Location</u></p>
<p>Montrose’s location is one of the best out of all of Houston’s neighborhoods. Montrose is literally within walking distance from downtown for some homes and only a minutes drive for others. In addition, Montrose features a short commute to other Houston business centers such as the Uptown Area and the Texas Medical Center. Since Montrose is so close to the center of Houston, Montrose features a relatively short commute, no matter where you need to go.</p>

<p><u>Entertainment</u></p>
<p>One of the main selling points of Montrose is that homes in the neighborhood have great accessibility to local entertainment hotspots. This includes Rice Village for fine dining and shopping, NRG Stadium for sporting events and the rodeo, the Museum District for a fun excursion, the Galleria for an enjoyable trip with friends, and much, much more. Within Montrose itself, the neighborhood is known for many great restaurants such as Nobie’s on Colquitt Street or Riel on Fairview Street. The delicious Common Bond Bakery resides in the montrose area as well. Additionally if you are feeling for a specific meal or another attraction you wanted to visit, Montrose has an ideal location and is accessible to all of Houston. Montrose’s culture and entertainment is what attracts many of its residents and is one of the main reasons the neighborhood is in such high demand.</p>

<p><u>Amenities</u></p>
<p>Homebuilding or moving to this neighborhood allows for access to multiple nearby parks. Some popular examples include Mandel Park, Cherryhurst Park, and Evan Chew Dog Park. These parks allow for various outdoor activities such as basketball, baseball, a weekend hike, or a picnic with the family.</p>
<p>In addition, Buffalo Bayou, which resides in the North of the neighborhood, is a popular choice for runners for their weekend run, bikers for their routes, and everyday residents for their afternoon stroll. Anyone moving into the Montrose neighborhood will be met with plenty of sunshine.</p>

<p><u>Schools</u></p>
<p>Families that are looking to move into the Montrose neighborhood will have a large number of great schools to choose from. Local public schools that homes in the neighborhood get zoned to include Wilson Elementary School, Lanier Middle School, and Carnegie Vanguard High School. Those looking into private schools as a potential option will be pleased to hear that both Annunciation Orthodox School and St. Steven Episcopal both reside in the area. In addition, many other private schools, such as St. Johns School and Episcopal High School are easily reachable within a daily commute. The schools in a neighborhood are an important consideration that every family must think about when moving to a new neighborhood. If gaining access to better schools is a priority, then the Montrose Neighborhood may be for you.</p>

<p><u>Conclusion</u></p>
<p>Montrose offers its residents an amazing location to the vast amount of local amenities, Montrose provides CRV Home’s homebuilding clients with everything they are looking for in a neighborhood. The amazing neighborhood combined with CRV Home’s custom homes allows people to piece together their perfect life.</p>

<p>If Montrose does not seem to be the right fit for you, please look into Houston’s other diverse array of neighborhoods. My previous blog posts on <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-west-university-place" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>West University Place</u></a> and <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-bellaire" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Bellaire</u></a> are both great places to start.</p>

<p>CRV Homes can help you build your dream home in Montrose or any one of Houston’s other diverse neighborhoods. To schedule your free idea session regarding home building in Houston and to get a free quote, contact CRV Homes today. <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/start" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Click here</u></a> to get started.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Building a Home in Bellaire]]></title><description><![CDATA[Overview Located in Southwest Houston of Downtown, Bellaire lies East of West University Place, but South of River Oaks and Memorial....]]></description><link>https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-bellaire</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6011acb728fa7b00174a3c7b</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 18:12:57 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/8231d7_1b8b61da32ca4595929c522779519298~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_682,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Daniel Cai</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><u>Overview</u></p>
<p>Located in Southwest Houston of Downtown, Bellaire lies East of West University Place, but South of River Oaks and Memorial. While often considered as a part of Houston, Bellaire is actually its own city as the City of Bellaire provides this neighborhood’s public utilities such as schools and parks. The majority of the land in Bellaire is residential and perfect for anyone looking to build a home. The city has a population of just over 17,000, is lined with large oak trees, and filled with custom built homes. The neighborhood as a whole is known by Houstonians for its exceptional location, amazing schools, and small town charm.</p>

<p><u>Location</u></p>
<p>Bellaire’s location is one reason many people choose to live or build a home in the neighborhood. Not only do residents have a quick commute to many of Houston’s business centers such as the Texas Medical Center, Houston Downtown, and the Uptown Area, but they also have easy access to many of Houston’s entertainment hotspots. This includes Rice Village for fine dinning and shopping, NRG Stadium for sporting events and the rodeo, the Houston Zoo for a fun excursion, the Galleria for an enjoyable trip with friends, and much, much more. Bellaire also offers a vast selection of dining locations from Jax Grill on Gaston Road to Broiler Burger on Bellaire Boulevard. And if you keep going down Bellaire Boulevard you will reach Houston’s Chinatown, which is the perfect place for anyone looking for a diverse selection of food. Bellaire’s location fits almost anyone’s needs and is one of the main reasons the neighborhood is in such high demand.</p>

<p><u>Amenities</u></p>
<p>Homebuilding or moving to this neighborhood grants access to multiple parks such as Bellaire-Zindler Park, Feld Park, Russ Pitman Park. With 14 parks total in the city, more information about what each one has to offer can be found here (https://www.bellairetx.gov/737/Park-Information). All of these parks are family friendly and allow for sports such as tennis, baseball, a weekend hike, or a picnic with the family. In addition, many of the major streets in the city offer a biking lane, which allows greater outdoor activities. For those looking for something more organized, the Recreational Center is Bellaire is the perfect choice. The center offers both a fitness center and programs for various activities. Finally, Bellaire offers multiple aquatic centers and an aquatic membership grants access to all of these facilities. Anyone looking for sunshine when moving to a new neighborhood will not be disappointed by Bellaire.</p>

<p><u>Schools</u></p>
<p>Anyone looking to move their families into the Bellaire neighborhood will have no shortage of great schools to choose from. Homes get zoned to local public schools including Condit Elementary School, Pin Oak Middle School, and Bellaire High School depending on the home’s exact location. In addition, some of Houston’s best private schools, such as Episcopal High School and St. John’s School, are close to the homes in Bellaire. The schools in a neighborhood is one of the most important aspects of moving locations for families, and getting access to better schools is one of the main reasons many choose to move to Bellaire.</p>

<p><u>Conclusion</u></p>
<p>Bellaire offers its residents a everything from an amazing location to a vast amount of local amenities. This neighborhood provides CRV Home’s homebuilding clients with everything they are looking for. This amazing neighborhood combined with CRV Home’s custom homes allows people to piece together their perfect life.</p>

<p>Whether you are currently thinking about building a home in Bellaire or are interested in homebuilding in any one of Houston’s diverse neighborhoods, CRV Homes is there to help. Contact CRV Homes today and schedule your free Idea Session regarding home building in the City of Bellaire.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Building a Home in West University Place]]></title><description><![CDATA[Overview Located in Southwest Houston, West University Place is East of Bellaire or Place and North of Braeswood Place. The neighborhood...]]></description><link>https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-in-west-university-place</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60072502fc50b200170c912d</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 18:32:02 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/8231d7_441ee21110ef40248f606804994f5f87~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_682,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Daniel Cai</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><u>Overview</u></p>
<p>Located in Southwest Houston, West University Place is East of Bellaire or Place and North of Braeswood Place. The neighborhood is known for its exceptional location, luxurious homes, and lavish lifestyle. As such, custom home building is one of the best ways to join this neighborhood. </p>

<p><u>Location</u></p>
<p>West University Place has a quick commute to many of Houston’s business centers such as the Texas Medical Center and Houston Downtown. In addition, the neighborhood is near many of Houston’s entertainment hotspots such as Rice Village, which is home to numerous stores, restaurants, and cafes that cater to anyone’s palette. The Houston Zoo, the Galleria, and NRG Stadium are all also highly accessible to residents in West University Place.</p>

<p><u>Amenities</u></p>
<p>Building in West University Place also allows for access to multiple parks such as Wier Park, Judson Park, and Huffington Park. All of these parks are family friendly and allow for sports such as basketball or tennis and are a great place to take your kids out for a lively outdoor adventure.</p>

<p><u>Schools</u></p>
<p>For families, homes in West University Place have access to local public schools including West U Elementary, Twain Elementary, Pin Oak Middle School, Pershing Middle School, Bellaire High School, and Lamar High School depending on the home’s exact location. In addition, homes in West University Place are in close proximity to some of Houston’s best private schools such as Episcopal High School and St. John’s School.</p>

<p><u>Community</u></p>
<p>West University place is one of Houston’s most walkable and friendliest neighborhoods. Residents can often be found on an afternoon stroll, walking their dogs, or running for exercise. In addition, members of this close knit community will often wave hi or smile at you while passing by, even if they seem like complete strangers. It is no wonder that West U features one of Houston’s lowest crime rates. Building a custom home in West University Place allows CRV Home’s clients to seamlessly join the community this neighborhood has fostered.</p>

<p><u>Conclusion</u></p>
<p>West University Place is and will continue to be one of Houston’s most desirable neighborhoods. From the amazing location to the vast amount of local amenities, West U provides CRV Home’s homebuilding clients with everything they are looking for in a neighborhood. The amazing neighborhood combined with CRV Home’s custom homes allows people to piece together their perfect life.</p>

<p>Whether you are currently thinking about building a home in West U or are interested in any aspect of homebuilding in any of Houston’s diverse neighborhoods, contact CRV Homes today and schedule your free Idea Session regarding home building in West University Place.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Turnkey Custom Home Building Options - Do you Own Land? Do you Need land?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Finding the right land/lot to construct a home requires time consuming research and analysis that even the average Houston Home builder...]]></description><link>https://www.crvhomes.com/post/turnkey-custom-home-building-options-do-you-own-land-do-you-need-land</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5f6df9e295c1ff001768d568</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 21:09:49 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/8231d7_183e6573a417436592aba009edd8bea2~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Ivan Bastidas</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>	Finding the right land/lot to construct a home requires time consuming research and analysis that even the average Houston Home builder does not aid or support in. At CRV Homes our Team prepares for any situation a potential home owner or investor may be starting the home building process from. Furthermore, the home building process will vary depending if the land is owned by the client or needed by the client. Therefore when looking to build a new custom home or project, a builder capable of guiding someone throughout the entirety of buying land, creating a perfect plan, & manifesting thoughts to reality is what our teams turnkey service provides.</p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/8231d7_183e6573a417436592aba009edd8bea2~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong><em><u>Do you Own Land? YES</u></em></strong></p>
<p>	If you own land and are ready to actively begin your custom home building project with a builder, then the next step is to schedule your free Idea Session. The Idea Session is where our design team is ready to help you identify your space needs, design preferences, and personal touches to create your perfect plan. Together we will establish the scope and budget for your project.</p>

<p>Helpful Note about <em><strong>what to consider about my land </strong></em>!!! - <a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/build-on-your-lot" target="_blank" rel="noopener">,,<u>ClickHere</u></a></p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/8231d7_04992677e43f415887a6af1920d1e40e~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_640,h_360,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong><em><u>Do you Need Land? YES</u></em></strong></p>
<p>	If you need land, our teams in house realtor can begin searching for a suitable piece of land for your custom home building project. To actively begin your custom home building project, then the next step is to schedule your free Idea Session. The Idea Session is where our design team is ready to help you identify your space needs, design preferences, and personal touches to create your perfect plan. Together we will establish the scope and budget for your project.</p>

<p><strong><em><u>Land Preparation for Development</u></em></strong></p>
<p>	Before any building truly begins, our team will complete a full site analysis. Additional pre-construction preparations include site clearing, demolition of existing structures, consideration of flood plain locations, survey evaluation, acquire necessary permits, and other essentials prior to construction.</p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c608d8_e3467237784540dd8f4d0ca5df02ed14~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_824,h_497,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>If you are planning to build a custom home and surfing the web for search terms like “custom home builder Houston”, go ahead and surf on over to “<a href="crvhomes.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>http://crvhomes.com</u></a>”. CRV Homes is a “Build on your lot Houston” home builder. CRV Homes is often touted as one of the “best home builders in Houston” and knows the importance of excellent customer service. CRV Homes has high ethical and professional standards, and are committed to providing their customers with exceptional services and quality products. Addition. The team at CRV Homes knows it is exciting to build a new home so their professionals keep you updated on progress via phone, text, email, and even photos - every step of the way!</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Professionals & Trades of the Houston Home Building Industry]]></title><description><![CDATA[The major activities required to build a home in Houston include Plans & Permitting, Site Preparation, Construction Tasks, Inspection...]]></description><link>https://www.crvhomes.com/post/the-professionals-trades-of-the-houston-home-building-industry</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5f6ca5b37c7ad70017b3ca88</guid><pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 21:19:35 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/c608d8_dae3607af49b496fbdd8bb979444498e~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Ivan Bastidas</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>	The major activities required to build a home in Houston include Plans & Permitting, Site Preparation, Construction Tasks, Inspection Management, and, of course, Professional Project Oversight. The Construction aspect of building a home does take the majority of the time (6 months of Scheduled work) in the overall process (12-18 months) from the <em>free Idea Session (Plan)</em> to <em>signing a contract & moving in to/selling (Implementations) </em>of a new project either as a new custom home or investment project. During Construction, different trade teams/crews will actively prepare the worksite for the subsequent team/crew to complete the next task until the completion of the new home or investment project.</p>

<p>	From the concrete driveway & framing of the garage to the utilities & painting of the home, different types of professional Trade Crews are necessary for each particular construction phase. For example, the Trades in charge of flooring and roofing cannot do their portion of a project if the trade crew in charge of framing & foundation work haven't even begun. Therefore to manage a custom home building project, builders need a professional working relationship with each respective trade.</p>

<p><u><strong>Decorated Ceiling Trim</strong></u></p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7c5397be0be4471d8d768a332fce65e6.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>	Trades within the Houston Custom Home Building Industry vary from Framing, Masonry, Tiling, Roofing, Cornice, Concrete, Electrical, Plumbing, Carpentry, & sometimes special trade contractors for specific details to the home. All though each trade crew may work at separate occasions, collectively are imperative for the completion of a well functional & beautiful masterpiece of a Home. </p>


<p>												  <strong><u>Modern Ceiling Trim</u></strong></p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/d090b7a8ad144a6cb319e0c25b8c6798.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>	For example, a crew may need to do something as detailed as the decorated ceiling trim work above versus a more modern type of ceiling trim work to the right. Trim adds a nice aesthetic to an empty room, and creates a sense of delicacy to the overall finish of a complete home. Practical functions of trim include covering imperfections to reflecting light in to otherwise somber areas of a home.</p>



<p> <strong><u><em>Conclusion</em></u></strong></p>
<p>	Without a Professional Builder, one may be able to learn the ins and outs of the Houston Home Building Industry, however the implementation of the acquired knowledge to then construct a quality home or project may be more costly and time consuming with a Chuck in a Truck in comparison to working along side a Professional Home Builder. Therefore, it's important to understand the relationship a builder has to a given trade for quality work. Since quality work is everything (20 Year Warranty), of course our team at CRV Homes builds strong relationships with all Trade Professionals. </p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c608d8_e3467237784540dd8f4d0ca5df02ed14~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_824,h_497,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>If you are planning to build a custom home and surfing the web for search terms like “custom home builder Houston”, go ahead and surf on over to “<a href="crvhomes.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>http://crvhomes.com</u></a>”. CRV Homes is a “Build on your lot Houston” home builder. CRV Homes is often touted as one of the “best home builders in Houston” and knows the importance of excellent customer service. CRV Homes has high ethical and professional standards, and are committed to providing their customers with exceptional services and quality products. Addition. The team at CRV Homes knows it is exciting to build a new home so their professionals keep you updated on progress via phone, text, email, and even photos - every step of the way!</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Energy Efficiency Talk ]]></title><description><![CDATA[There are so many options, systems, and gadgets available that are designed to improve the energy efficiency of a home. The best...]]></description><link>https://www.crvhomes.com/post/energy-efficiency-talk</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5f40283906fbfc00174210b5</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 04:09:27 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/484b935214aa4750a37c87f871a0f836.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Jeffrey R. Rodgers</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/484b935214aa4750a37c87f871a0f836.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>There are so many options, systems, and gadgets available that are designed to improve the energy efficiency of a home. The best opportunity to make the greatest strides to that goal is during the building process. </p>

<p>An energy efficient home is a result of planning and design. The home will provide higher levels of comfort and performance while delivering a noticeable cost savings. As well, the energy efficient house will sell for 8% more, on average. It makes sense to build a home with energy efficient systems and features. You don't have to go overboard by trying to add every option and feature on the market to achieve a well-performing, energy efficient home. The topics discussed below are a great starting point and, installed properly, will produce excellent results that will last for many years. </p>

<p>Exterior Of The Home</p>
<p>During the framing process, there are a couple of very important, long-last items that can be applied to control the air flow from outside to in and control moisture. Water membrane house wrap or a similar product is a material that wraps completely around the outside of the house to create a barrier between the outside air and the house. House wrap protects the framing in the walls by allowing moisture vapor to escape while preventing air and moisture. Installed correctly, with the top piece overlapping the lower pieces, the joints and penetrations taped, and edges at door and windows taped, this material will perform for many years at a very high level. Prior to covering the exterior with siding, brick, stone or other materials, it's a great idea to have the house wrap inspected by a professional to insure proper installation. House wrap is an important part of the energy efficiency plan and is difficult to access after the finish is installed. </p>

<p>Sill sealer is an unfaced Styrofoam product which serves as a 3/16' gasket between the sill plate (bottom plate) and the slab or floor. Sill sealer is closed cell foam and unaffected by water or dirt. For the cost to install, a sill sealer is a must-have when building a home. </p>

<p>Interior Of The Home</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c608d8_06dcd6ec45974cc496082d8a1f2d94bf~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_992,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Insulation,  the most well-known and obvious of the energy efficiency tools, is a system designed to mitigate temperature transfer from outside to in. There are many options including spray foam insulation, blown fiberglass, blown cellulose, and Styrofoam. The most common insulation used in the Houston area is fiberglass batts in the walls and blown fiberglass in the attic. Builders use variations of these insulation methods based on their experiences and opinions and in some cases, even create a hybrid, or combination of different materials to achieve their goals. Ask you builder which methods will be used in your home and research and compare. Upon completion of the installation, have the frame and insulation inspected by a energy efficiency rater to insure proper installation. </p>


<p>Polyseal has become a fundamental part of air sealing a house properly. Polyseal is the process of applying spray foam insulation where the sill plate meets the slab or floor, in all outside corners, and a bead along to lower top plate where the ceiling meets attic area. In addition to these areas, all penetrations from the outside should be sealed as well as any penetrations from the first floor to second. The space between all doors and windows should be filled with poly. </p>

<p>Typically, this process is completed by the insulation provider. There are polyseal specialists for hire and this is an opportunity to take your air sealing to the next level. The R-value goals should be determined during the planning stages of a home. Using the correct materials, installing them properly, and having the insulation inspected by a qualified inspector will lower energy costs from the day you move in. A good insulation installation will yield high-performance, comfort, and a significant savings on your energy use. </p>
<p>	</p>
<p>Windows And Doors</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/11062b_38bd46ba9c7b43cc9bf7aee415110349~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>All windows and doors are not created equal. It is important that the windows used in your home are high-</p>

<p>efficiency windows with features that include Low-E, double-glazed, and a special coating on the glass to reflect heat. Window technology is changing daily and it gets difficult to keep up. Energy Star is a great source for information and updates to the window efficiency ratings. All windows need to be installed properly and the opening for the window needs to be filled with polyseal. </p>
<p>Windows and doors provide an opportunity to step up the efficiency and performance of your home. An emphasis should be placed on quality and efficiency with regards to both.</p>

<p>Appliances</p>
<p>Appliances can have a profound impact on the overall efficiency of your home. Select appliances that perform the tasks you will use them for but that are Energy Star certified. You can identify them by the two purchase prices on the appliance. One is the purchase price and the second is the cost of operating the product. Check with <a href="energystar.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Energy Star</u></a> for the full list of benefits of an Energy Star certified appliance. </p>

<p>The water heater is the second highest source of energy use in the home. Special attention should be used to choose the best system for your home. Tankless hot water heating units provide excellent performance by heating only the water that you need and save space. Take a look at this option for a high efficiency performer. Standard water heater tanks con be very efficient as well. Look the the Energy Star label  and compare the cost of use tags found on Energy Star labelled water heaters. These tags will help you find the correct energy efficient application for your home.</p>

<p>High efficiency heating and air conditioning system and equipment is one of the best ways to save on energy costs. About half of your monthly energy bill is being used to condition the air in the home and heat the temperature where you want it. That being said, it makes good sense to use high efficiency, quality equipment. There is a science to designing a system that is effective and efficient. Professional heating and air specialists are a great source of information as there are several factors that go into designing a system for a specific house. Allow those professionals to guide you through this installation.</p>

<p>EPA</p>
<p>The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) offers three certifications that are of interest with regard to efficiency, conservation, and comfort of your home. </p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c608d8_ee1844278d5243d196e2cb9ef6b9260c~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_700,h_350,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>1) Energy Star provides credible, unbiased information so consumers can make well-informed decisions. They provide cost effective approaches to energy management with the goal of saving energy in your home. The products labeled with Energy Star label has been tested and proven to use less energy and perform on a high level. Energy Star certified houses are at least 10% more efficient than houses built to code and offer better comfort, performance, and quality. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c608d8_e5e7999b5a0742fe9bc14d2fb9c22bdf~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_700,h_525,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>2) WaterSense label identifies products that use at least 20% less water, save energy, and offer at least the same performance as other products. It becomes important when you consider how many fixtures in your house apply to this efficiency standard. Toilets, shower heads, faucets, and irrigation controllers are all part of the WaterSense program and should be a part of your efficiency plan.</p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c608d8_e00df7d3003d47dfbe17e3ecb63cb424~mv2_d_2806_1452_s_2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>3) Clean air is important to everyone. Indoor airPlus is an EPA  labeling program requiring builders to use practices and products which minimize exposure to pollutants and contaminants. Building on the Energy Star requirements, Indoor airPlus requires a thorough list of specs to provide comprehensive indoor air quality protections in new homes. </p>
<p>Moisture control through better roof, wall, and foundation drainage, radon-resistant construction techniques, pest control, cleaner air, better ventilation, and materials with fewer chemicals are some of the benefits of the Indoor airPlus building practices. </p>

<p>CRV Homes is one of very few builders in Houston area who is committed to building all of their homes up to the EPA standards for energy efficiency, water conservation and air purity.</p>

<p>Building a custom home that is efficient, performs on a very high level, and requires minimal maintenance is possible through smart home technologies that are available and evolving today. Ask you builder about each of these opportunities to be responsible, environmentally friendly, and  build your dream home. Call CRV Homes today. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c608d8_e3467237784540dd8f4d0ca5df02ed14~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_824,h_497,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>If you are planning to build a custom home and surfing the web for search terms like “custom home builder Houston”, go ahead and surf on over to “http://crvhomes.com”. CRV Homes is a “Build on your lot Houston” home builder. CRV Homes is often touted as one of the “best home builders in Houston” and knows the importance of excellent customer service. CRV Homes has high ethical and professional standards, and are committed to providing their customers with exceptional services and quality products. Addition. The team at CRV Homes knows it is exciting to build a new home so their professionals keep you updated on progress via phone, text, email, and even photos - every step of the way!</p>
<p>
</p>
<p>CRV Homes is a responsible builder and environmentally friendly!</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Finding The Perfect Lot for Your Dream Home]]></title><description><![CDATA[More and more Houston residents are choosing to build their dream home for the numerous benefits it offers. After all, building a home...]]></description><link>https://www.crvhomes.com/post/finding-the-perfect-lot-for-your-dream-home</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5f2cde59ce536f00172f5e90</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:45:49 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/56b1ad182bb349119217cef75d1ec0a7.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Jeffrey R. Rodgers</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/56b1ad182bb349119217cef75d1ec0a7.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>More and more Houston residents are choosing to build their dream home for the numerous benefits it offers. After all, building a home gives them the freedom to design their floor plan, site plan, and landscaping any way that best fits their lifestyle and preferences. One of the challenges that will come up early in the process is finding the right lot to build the house on.</p>

<p>Here are some considerations to keep in mind when selecting a lot for your new home.</p>

<p>1) Pick the right area</p>
<p>Everyone wants to live in an area that is known for its nice-looking homes and offers amenities. However, there are many other factors to consider when assessing the suitability of a neighborhood.</p>

<p>Buyers should start by making a list of available lots that are in the area you wish to live. This list can be narrowed down based on your unique needs and preferences.</p>
<p>Areas that are less developed today should not be overlooked. Although these areas may not seem like desirable places to live now, future developments in the area could boost property values significantly. For this reason, purchasing a lot in a new or underdeveloped area may turn out to be a good investment.</p>

<p>Buyers should also consider in their own future needs. For example, you may have no interest is the area schools now. As your family changes, that may be a factor at some point. </p>

<p>2) Visit the lot in-person</p>
<p>Once you have chosen an area that fits your needs, you should visit it in-person. Reading about an area gives you only a limited amount of information about what living there is actually like. So, get in your car and drive down to the potential site of your new home. Exploring the area can help you make sure you will enjoy life in your new neighborhood. </p>

<p>Look at the boundary around the lot and observe how close the neighboring property is. Will your neighbor’s home be blocking the view from certain rooms in your home? </p>
<p>Similarly, if the lot is next to a large building, your home may be shielded from natural sunlight for a large portion of the day. This could be desirable or undesirable, depending on your unique situation.</p>

<p>Also consider the proximity of the lot to major roads and intersections. If the lot is close to a busy intersection, you will have to deal with traffic crossing regularly and the noise it generates. Property owners that are not bothered by the sound of cars may still get disturbed by the headlights from passing vehicles at night. 
</p>
<p>You should also check out the lot at different times of the day and learn how it changes. Some streets that seem quiet during the daytime may get busier at night. For instance, this could be the case if your neighbors throw social events regularly, which could generate excessive noise and make it harder to find parking on your street at night.</p>

<p>3.	Topographic considerations</p>
<p>It is important to check the different features of your lot before deciding on it. Some objects, such as rocks or trees, may need to be removed before you can start construction. Consider the driveway access options and how that will affect the overall project. </p>

<p>You should also check to see how level the property is. A property that is situated on a slight incline may be desirable due to the easy drainage this sloping provides. A slightly steeper slope could require excessive fill to level enough of the lot to set the house properly.</p>

<p>Another consideration is privacy. The lot should provide room for the house to sit on the lot so that neighbors can't see directly inside, headlights of passing vehicles aren’t disruptive from inside the home, and the porches and patios offer the preferred level of privacy and comfort at the right time of the day.</p>

<p>4.	Access to utilities </p>
<p>It can be tempting to choose a lot that is far away from other properties. After all, a lot that is in a secluded location will offer unobstructed views and more privacy. However, it may also be far away from electricity and water lines. </p>

<p>For this reason, you should bring your builder with you when you are looking at different lots. A professional can evaluate a lot and let you know how difficult or costly it will be to set up utilities for your dream home. </p>

<p>5.	Picture your home on the lot</p>
<p>The final step is to picture your completed property on the lot. This may seem trivial in comparison to all the other considerations, but it is important nonetheless. </p>
<p>Constructing a property can be a huge investment, so you should ensure you are happy with your lot choice before moving forward with it.</p>

<p>Now that you know the different ways to assess the suitability of a lot, you should get in touch with an CRV Homes and let the experienced Build On Your Lot professionals guide you through this process and turn your vision into your dream home.</p>

<p>If you are planning to build a custom home and surfing the web for search terms like “custom home builder Houston”, go ahead and surf on over to “http://crvhomes.com”. CRV Homes is a “Build on your lot Houston” home builder. CRV Homes is often touted as one of the “best home builders in Houston” and knows the importance of excellent customer service. CRV Homes has high ethical and professional standards, and are committed to providing their customers with exceptional services and quality products. Addition. The team at CRV Homes knows it is exciting to build a new home so their professionals keep you updated on progress via phone, text, email, and even photos - every step of the way!</p>

<p>CRV Homes is a responsible builder and environmentally friendly!</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c608d8_e3467237784540dd8f4d0ca5df02ed14~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_824,h_497,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Build On Your Lot In Houston</p>
<p>888-993-7871</p>
<p><a href="https://l.facebook.com/l.php?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.buildinhouston.com%2F%3Ffbclid%3DIwAR02YYImWNDDWpKINtDoEg9K1aDGDp8p2MRvDK9IeJPNDmmdJLKZPN_qMww&h=AT3p3HUUPRPTEcXnUbs6lxQgEzFyno_sKfZP05dY0tlNK60VvEA34YoWSSrvfrDNJIk9dNQa_Nq9pY3euXmrZObYNcS5IEwEAdL1Qah4wrJfBWSkF4FMemT02MFp7FLkuStaJBdU973t7fqsIQ&__tn__=-UK-R&c[0]=AT3YlrbcIJuqmYKbTQHq3x0k-12mECL2hYcz10DVzjgh1slRDgVUHarEN6ZPCZXRHRBjkUYGGlMnhbZKUV86iQ9lyi1poYdCpQL4YM-gDaH-Rx8nb5ruP3IL2bRPibRp78KLljusz0N8-Vy-sK9vjfKwsSehvnU9LplDKdEPFsfI9ml4gr38x2qLSMypgw" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>www.buildinhouston.com</u></a></p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Building a Home vs Buying]]></title><description><![CDATA[The most obvious benefit of constructing your own home is having the ability to customize it...]]></description><link>https://www.crvhomes.com/post/building-a-home-vs-buying</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5f22ed5ba415260017cf3e33</guid><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 05:20:20 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/c608d8_cae0f0f3775b4b9a862fed65d47bc0b7~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_675,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Jeffrey R. Rodgers</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c608d8_cae0f0f3775b4b9a862fed65d47bc0b7~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_675,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Many Houston residents are on the fence about whether they should acquire an existing home or build their own. This guide will compare the advantages and drawbacks of each option to help you make an informed decision. Let’s start by looking at the pros and cons of building a custom home.</p>

<p>Pros and cons of building your own home</p>

<p>Building a home can be an exciting experience for prospective homeowners. However, this route does come with its ups and downs. For this reason, it’s important to look at the benefits and challenges that come with constructing a home before taking the plunge.</p>

<p>Pros of building a custom home</p>

<p><strong><u>Customization</u></strong></p>
<p>The most obvious benefit of constructing your own home is having the ability to customize it, however you please. If you are building your home from the ground, you will have the freedom to choose the floor plan and elevations, select the type of flooring you want, and add custom features, and select colors to reflect your tastes, preferences and needs. At <a href="www.buildinhouston.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>CRV Homes</u></a>, we are a true custom builder and the endless options and selections are made by our clients with the guidance of our in-house designer.</p>

<p><strong><u>Modern features and components</u></strong></p>
<p>Building your own home also gives you a chance to add modern features and finishes to it. You can use the latest energy-efficient materials, such as Energy Star-certified roofs </p>
<p>and insulated siding during the initial construction phase. These materials could help </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a27d24_c38b0f4125d94916a61c9517387ed5eb~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_768,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>protect your home from the elements and reduce your heating bill in the future. </p>
<p>Some items, such as insulation or preferred lighting, can be difficult, or in some cases the existing structure. Being able to include your desired features, components, and colors during the initial construction phase offers flexibility, better results, and preserves the warranties on the installed features.</p>

<p><strong><u>Ensuring fixtures are installed correctly</u></strong></p>
<p>Older homes sometimes suffer from problems, such as leaky roofs, foundation issues, grading issues, and poor insulation, due to improper fitting practices, typical settling and aging. When building your own home, you can ensure that these items are fitted properly, installed per manufacturer specs, and operate properly. This can save you from running into problems in the future.</p>

<p><strong><u>Saving on costs</u></strong></p>
<p>It is believed that constructing a new home can be <a href="https://www.realtor.com/advice/buy/is-it-cheaper-to-buy-or-build-a-house/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">more expensive</a> than purchasing an existing home. However, the practice of building a home from the ground up can be the more affordable option when you consider the costs of purchasing an existing home and renovating it to include desired features. In many cases, upon completion of a CRV Homes built custom home, our clients move into their home with considerable equity.  The value in building a home with CRV Homes is that when you move in, you have the floor plan you want, the features you want, in the location you want, often at no extra charge. </p>

<p>Cons of building a custom home</p>

<p><strong><u>Construction time</u></strong></p>
<p>The biggest drawback of building a custom home is that construction takes a fair amount of time. If you plan to move to a new property, you will have to wait until construction is completed. A new home can take anywhere from <a href="https://www.realtor.com/advice/buy/how-long-does-it-take-to-build-a-house/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3 to 8 months</a> to finish, depending on the size and complexity of the project. This process can get delayed if the building-process is interrupted by bad weather or material availability.</p>

<p><strong><u>Unexpected costs</u></strong></p>
<p>When you start construction on a new property, it can be difficult to estimate what the total cost of the project will be. Unexpected lot preparation costs and material price increases can cause you to exceed your initial budget. These sudden expenses may prevent you from customizing your home in the manner you initially envisioned. At CRV Homes, we will quote you a price to build your home on your lot, from initial consultation to and through the warranty period. Only custom features that are added during construction will affect the price. </p>

<p><strong><u>Supervising construction</u></strong></p>
<p>Homeowners are expected to supervise and keep track of construction activities for their project. This can be difficult if they have busy lives and other responsibilities to focus on. </p>

<p>If you are using the services of a contractor or a home builder, you may still need to keep an eye on construction activities to ensure that they are going according to plan. </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c608d8_1a66eaadcc0741a8b746998341a92a2f~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><a href="www.buildinhouston.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>CRV Homes</u></a> will be on your jobsite daily to supervise the build-out. We will provide regular reports via email from start to finish. While we encourage you to visit the site as part of enjoying the custom home process, CRV Homes does not expect that you will need to supervise any part the construction process. The construction managers at CRV Homes are very experienced custom home builders having supervised over 700 homes. </p>
<p>Pros of purchasing an existing home</p>

<p><strong><u>Less effort than constructing a home</u></strong></p>
<p>Buying an existing home can be tempting. After all, someone else took care of the planning and construction for you. This frees you from the burden of purchasing land and picking out a home design.</p>

<p><strong><u>Moving in on short notice</u></strong></p>
<p>As mentioned earlier, constructing a home can take several months. This can be a problem for people who need to move on short notice.</p>

<p>Purchasing an existing home is generally a shorter process, and can be completed in around <a href="https://www.bankrate.com/real-estate/how-long-does-it-take-to-buy-a-house/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">30 to 45 days</a>. However, this does not factor in the amount of time it takes to browse through listings, select a property, and on the other end, renovate the property to include desired and updated features.</p>

<p><strong><u>Negotiating a lower price</u></strong></p>
<p>Purchasing an existing home also gives you the ability to negotiate for a lower price. While you can also negotiate with a builder to build your home, you will have more flexibility to negotiate an existing home based on the list of faults provided by an inspection report, if you choose to hire an inspector. </p>
<p>Hiring a professional real estate agent to provide guidance through this process and then hiring professional contractors to make the suggested repairs will provide you the most desirable results</p>

<p>Cons of purchasing an existing home</p>

<p><strong><u>Renovation costs</u></strong></p>
<p>If you have chosen to purchase an existing home, you may have to renovate it to suit your tastes and needs. For example, a person who uses a wheelchair may need to make changes to their home to make it wheelchair accessible. This can lead to additional costs on top of your initial purchase.</p>

<p><strong><u>Old fixtures and components</u></strong></p>
<p>Existing homes are also less likely to possess modern fixtures and components. As a result, you may have to deal with problems, such as outdated wall ceiling textures or leaky roofs that are not up to code or standards. Your heating bill could also be higher due to inefficient outdated air-conditioning system, the poor lighting may detract from the functionality of the space, or the kitchen may limit your enjoyment because of outdated or missing features. </p>

<p>Should I build my home or purchase an existing one?</p>
<p>As you can see, constructing a home and purchasing an existing one both offer their own advantages and drawbacks. The option that is right for you will depend on your unique situation. </p>

<p>If your focus is on customization, it will be far easier to construct a home to fit your needs. However, if you need to move to a new location on short notice, purchasing a pre-existing home could be the better option.</p>

<p><a href="www.buildinhouston.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>CRV Homes</u></a> provides a turnkey custom home building option. Please contact us to learn more about how our experienced  team of builders, designers, and real estate professionals can make the process seamless, easy, and fun.  </p>

<p><a href="www.buildinhouston.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>CRV Homes:</u></strong><u> </u><strong><u>,<em>Your Vision. Our Team. Dream Home</em></u></strong></a></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c608d8_e3467237784540dd8f4d0ca5df02ed14~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_824,h_497,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>If you are planning to build a custom home and surfing the web for search terms like “<strong>custom home builder Houston</strong>”, go ahead and surf on over to “<a href="http://crvhomes.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">,<strong>http://crvhomes.com</strong></a>”. CRV Homes is a “<a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/build-on-your-lot" target="_blank" rel="noopener">,<strong><u>Build on your lot Houston</u></strong></a>” home builder. Some like to search for <em>"</em><a href="https://www.crvhomes.com/start" target="_blank" rel="noopener">,<u><em>Custom Home Builder near me</em></u></a><em>"</em> to find CRV Homes whom is often touted as one of the “<a href="crvhomes.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">,<strong><u>best home builders in Houston</u></strong></a>” and knows the importance of excellent customer service. CRV Homes has high ethical and professional standards, and are committed to providing their customers with exceptional services and quality products. Addition. The team at CRV Homes knows it is exciting to build a new home so their professionals keep you updated on progress via phone, text, email, and even photos - every step of the way!</p>
<p> </p>
<p>CRV Homes is a responsible builder and environmentally friendly!</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Prepare Now to Buy a New Home this Summer!]]></title><description><![CDATA[If summer looks like the time you’ll be buying a new home, now may seem be too soon to start trying to pin down a specific property. But...]]></description><link>https://www.crvhomes.com/post/prepare-now-to-buy-a-new-home-this-summer</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5d0bc593d4986800161773c8</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 17:53:45 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/c608d8_fcfb366019d6474fb55ce5e5af16be33~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_318,h_159,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Jeffrey R. Rodgers</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p> </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c608d8_fcfb366019d6474fb55ce5e5af16be33~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_318,h_159,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="With CRV Homes you get a full-service, turnkey home-building experience at a fixed cost!" alt="www.BuildInHouston.com"></figure><p>If summer looks like the time you’ll be buying a new home, now may seem be too soon to start trying to pin down a specific property. But with a few months to go, it’s time to lay the groundwork. </p>
<p> </p>
<p>After all, you’ll need to get your finances in shape, know how to get your best deal on a mortgage, and figure out where, within your budget, you want to live. These things take time, but start now and by the end of winter you’ll be ready to house hunt and then spring into action when you find “the one.”</p>

<p><strong>Price range and downpayment. </strong>Most banks and online real estate sites have affordability and mortgage calculators that can help you figure out what you can afford. </p>
<p>Work out your own price range based on what the calculators say. Do those monthly payments look reasonable or like a stretch? Do you expect your monthly expenses to rise, maybe because of a planned car purchase? How long do you expect to stay in this house? Is it worth a bit of a stretch because you plan to stay more than five to seven years? Or would you be more comfortable keeping payments at a lower level?</p>
<p>To determine how much you’ll have for a downpayment, assess what you have in hand and what you can realistically save between now and spring. Don’t forget there will be closing costs. Downpayment calculators will show how much you need for each downpayment percentage required for different types of mortgage.</p>

<p><strong>Neighborhood. </strong>Start to figure out where, within your budget, would suit you in the ways most important to you — schools, ease of commute, housing density, amenities. Which factors are most important, which are more open to compromise?</p>
<p>Check out online real estate listings to find out more about what is likely to be on the market and to help you focus in on areas that meet your needs. Keep tabs online on some listings that interest you — see how quickly they sell, whether they undergo price changes as they stay on the market, what they ultimately sell for.</p>
<p>Go to open houses. By looking at houses before you’re actively shopping, you’ll learn how to look effectively. You’ll get better at seeing the details, noticing the important factors, and getting past a first impression to what will really matter.</p>

<p><strong>Credit score. </strong>Check your credit report — to know your score and to see if there is anything you want to dispute. You can order free credit reports from each of the three major credit reporting agencies through annualcreditreport.com, the only authorized website for free credit reports, according to the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.</p>
<p>Your credit score will be key to the mortgage interest rate you can get. Between now and when you apply, here’s how to maintain or improve your score:</p><ul>
  <li>Be sure to pay bills on time. </li>
  <li>Payment history is a top factor for lenders.</li>
  <li>Pay down credit card debt as much as you can while still saving for your down payment.</li>
  <li>Avoid applying for new credit cards or closing old ones. Both can decrease your credit score.</li>
</ul><p><strong>Mortgage. </strong>First, check out mortgage rates at various lenders. You’re not ready to apply for a mortgage yet, so you won’t get specific quotes. But many lenders post approximate rates online, and you can browse them regularly so that you get to know the lay of the land.</p>

<p>A month or so before you’re hoping to buy, start shopping for a mortgage. Ask for quotes on rates and closing fees from several lenders. Once you identify the mortgage company, get a pre-approval letter from the lender. With that in hand, you’ll be able to show that you’re a good prospect as a buyer.</p>

<p>For more advice on buying a new home or building a new home, please contact Houstonian Capital Investments at <strong>888-993-7871</strong> or <strong>info@BuildInHouston.com</strong> or visit our website at <strong>BuildInHouston.com</strong>. </p>

<p>We provide a full-service, turnkey home-building experience at a fixed cost! Our one-of-a-kind solution makes building your dream home easy. We take care of everything for you! Your plans or ours, the result is the same...High Quality, Energy Efficient, Smart Homes. Contact us today and find out what we can do for you.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 Questions You Must Ask Before Hiring a Houston Home Builder]]></title><description><![CDATA[Building a new home is the largest investment most people will make in their lifetime. It is very important that you get it right the...]]></description><link>https://www.crvhomes.com/post/5-questions-you-must-ask-before-hiring-a-houston-home-builder</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c6bb5c1abccd2001c5f6953</guid><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:08:15 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/58a5eae4c299257d936b72e59167c178.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Jeffrey R. Rodgers</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<hr><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c608d8_228473ebd7f14613901b34e2e63508ed~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_576,h_833,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Building a new home is the largest investment most people will make in their lifetime. It is very important that you get it right the first time. You don't want to just hire "Chuck in a Truck" to build your new home. You will want to hire only the best new home builder. </p>

<p>There is a lot more to it than just choosing the best custom home builder for your project. While there are many good builders in Houston, finding a good builder is only one aspect of building a new home. It is essential to get all of the aspects correct on the first try to ensure success. </p>

<p>You should take steps to ensure that your project is on time, on budget and meets your quality standards. It is essential is to hire a builder who can take this enormous challenge off of your shoulders. Your builder should handle all of the many facets of the new home building process for you, 100% turnkey. As the owner, you always want to be in a position where everything that goes wrong during the construction process is the builder's responsibility to address. This helps avoid finger pointing and you’re not left on the hook for problems that arise. For example, hiring an architect that you thought seemed great, but drafted a set of flawed plans city inspectors keep rejecting.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Believe it or not, this is an advantage for the builder also. More often than not, when owners attempt to “help” the builder by “getting the plans” or “doing the demo”, it results in added costs, additional problems, delays and frustrations in the process almost every time. If you are serious about hiring the best new home building company for your project, you need to learn what you should be asking them. </p>

<p>Remember, you will likely be working together for 6 to 12 months in a business relationship. So as in any relationship, there needs to be trust and clear, honest communication. Here is what you should be asking to make sure you are getting what you need - which is a 100% turnkey new home builder.</p><hr><h2>1. Are you a 100% turnkey builder? </h2><p>The answer should be unequivocally “YES”. If not, either prepare to work your rear end off and pay a lot more money for additional professional services, or run. Those are your options. You should be selecting a builder who can provide you a turnkey price which includes the following:</p><ul>
  <li>Pre-Construction Cost Analysis & Construction Consulting; </li>
  <li>Land Surveying and, if required, Replatting Services;</li>
  <li>Demolition Services, as required;</li>
  <li>Professional Design Advisory;</li>
  <li>Architectural Drawings and Engineered Structural Plans;  </li>
  <li>Building Permits and Accompanying Affidavits; </li>
  <li>Construct Project Management & Oversight, Materials and Labor;</li>
  <li>Trash Services, Portable Restroom Services & Security Fencing; and</li>
  <li>Post-Construction Warranty Service.</li>
</ul><p>CRV Homes is a great example of a Builder providing all of the above services and many more. CRV Homes offers new construction Houston homes starting at a standard price of $120 per square foot for homebuyers and those who would like to build on your lot.</p><hr><h2>2. What is your reputation and how do I know if you are credible?</h2><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c608d8_c7cbbe4ac2774064a8046dfd7242b6aa~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_876,h_117,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>You should select a builder that is a good standing member of the Greater Houston Builders Association, Texas Association of Builders and National Association of Home Builders. If you are working with a builder who isn’t, perhaps you aren’t dealing with a real builder at all. Maybe it is just “Chuck in a truck”, and you should keep looking for the right builder.</p>

<p>At CRV Homes, we are active and contributing members of the above associations and we make continuing education a priority. Our homes are inspected by engineers to ensure compliance with building codes and our stringent quality requirements. We utilize third party consultants to perform inspections during and after completion on every home. Our professional builders conduct daily project management and oversight of all work. You should make sure that your builder does the same.</p><hr><h2>3. Do you have “Green” and energy efficient building practices?</h2><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c608d8_e2a9bdc07538436fa7ce38f546e2b32c~mv2_d_1523_1248_s_2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>This can be a tricky question. Why? Because anyone can just say they build “green” and energy efficient. But you need to dig just a little bit further and find out what specifically the builder does to validate their assertions. </p>

<p>For comparison sake, like many other builders, CRV Homes also commits to building green, energy efficient homes. We are environmentally responsible and build using materials, appliances, and mechanical systems that reduce the carbon footprint and decrease energy consumption in our homes. As a result, our homes are more energy efficient and you save on utility bills.</p>

<p>For example, our homes have reduced energy consumption by using LED lighting and advanced thermo-insulating installation techniques. We also provide a Tech-Shield Radiant Barrier, roof ventilation, 16 SEER HVAC systems, and programmable thermostats. Our appliances are Energy Star rated and we use Low-E windows. Most importantly, a third party energy HERS rating firms inspects our completed homes and certifies them with an energy certificate of efficiency. You should make sure that your builder does the same.</p><hr><h2>4. Will I get a Smart Home technology package included for no additional cost?</h2><p>Okay, it’s 2019! It would be quite frankly a little silly to build any new home that doesn't automatically include Smart Home technology. You shouldn't have to ask when you buy a brand new car if it has power windows and speakers - nowadays most new cars come standard with much more than that. Why should a new home be any different? Unfortunately, "Chuck in a Truck" may not see it that way so you need to be careful.</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c608d8_aa1a6b73e91546fa9020e626ffc5de72~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_700,h_467,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>For example, buying a CRV Home includes smart home technology as a standard feature. We have partnered with technology companies to build the leading-edge solutions right into your new home at no additional cost. With CRV Homes, your new Smart Home is the standard! It is built right into your new home.</p>

<p>We are including on all new homes contracted in 2019 a Nest Smart Home technology package. Our package includes a Nest Video Doorbell and Outdoor Camera. Also included is a Nest Thermostat, Levition WiFi Light Switches, and USB charging ports. For your added security we include a Nest x Yale Front Door Lock.</p><hr><h2>5. What kind of warranty do you offer and how does it work? </h2><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c608d8_d188eb2a52d441d495660b272a3df60e~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_233,h_181,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>In Texas, new home builders are required to provide you with a warranty by law - but the warranty requirements aren't very clear and that's not good for home buyers. Some builders use the standard TREC contract, while more professional builders have their own contracts outlining their warranties, which are typically better for you because they include higher standards and specifics. In each type of contract, the builder makes no warranties other than those set forth elsewhere in the contract, in a separate document, or as provided by law. The first two are easy to figure out—if such conditions or documents don’t exist, there are no other warranties.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>But what about those warranties “provided by law”?</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Current Texas law provides two implied warranties in connection with new home construction:</p><ul>
  <li>Implied Warranty of Good Workmanship; and</li>
  <li>Implied Warranty of Habitability.</li>
</ul><p>A buyer can file suit against a builder if a new home isn’t constructed in a good and workmanlike manner, using industry standards. It also must be suitable for habitation, safe and sanitary. Claims based on a breach of these implied warranties provided by law may require legal action to determine the merit of any such claims.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>We appreciate the importance of excellent customer service - to keep you satisfied. CRV Homes stand by our quality craftsmanship and back it up with our express limited warranty. Our warranty includes a 1-year workmanship warranty, 2-year major mechanical warranty, and a 10-year structural warranty. The products in your home are also protected with product warranties from trusted, reputable manufacturers we work with. CRV Homes is proud of the robust warranty we provide our valued homeowners. We're always looking to give you the best service possible!</p>

<p>In conclusion, please remember that building a new home is a huge financial and emotional investment. Please take the extra time to do a thorough check on any prospective builder's workmanship, references, and credentials. There are a lot more questions you should be asking once you identify the right builder for you. Finding and choosing the right custom home builder for your project may be difficult and possibly awkward at times. You are embarking on one of the biggest purchases of your life so you need to be confident in your decision. Do your homework and understand the process and you will reap the rewards with a beautiful home built to your specifications. </p>

<p>And remember, you want to use a builder who is 100% turnkey. If you would like to contact CRV Homes to see how we can help build you a quality, efficient, smart home, please come see us at www.BuildinHouston.com. Our phone number is on the front page so feel free to call or chat live online anytime. We would be happy to talk to you. </p>

<p>By the way, one last shameless plug... CRV Homes knows the importance of excellent customer service. CRV Homes has high ethical and professional standards, and we are committed to providing our customers with exceptional services and quality products. Additionally, we know it is exciting to build a new home so our construction professionals keep you updated on progress via phone, text, email, and even photos - every step of the way!</p>

<p>We try our hardest to be a responsible builder and environmentally friendly!</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c608d8_4c6b5ca7e23349bba114d8b253634961~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_449,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why Homebuyers in Houston, Texas Should Build their Next Home]]></title><description><![CDATA[Why should Houston homebuyers build a home vs. buying a used home? N.B. – First, homebuyers need to understand that building a new home...]]></description><link>https://www.crvhomes.com/post/why-you-should-build-your-home</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c76f5380a2463001ca3f2a2</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 21:41:33 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/df746fe6775147b983050b6d6ac6a8ba.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Noe I. Bastidas</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/df746fe6775147b983050b6d6ac6a8ba.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><h2><strong>Why should Houston homebuyers build a home vs. buying a used home?</strong></h2>
<p>N.B. – First, homebuyers need to understand that building a new home is a financially viable option for the middle class. There is a misconception that building a new home is only for the rich, that the cost of building is more expensive than buying a used home. And that is simply not true.</p><hr><h2><strong>Can you elaborate? Perhaps with an example.</strong></h2><p>N.B. – Absolutely. Let’s walk through an example based on the current, 2019, real estate market in the East End and Near Northside areas of Houston. These are highly desirable market areas for homebuyers looking to live inside the 610 Loop, near Downtown in up-in-coming neighborhoods.</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c608d8_e19a2c17a25940aeaf14116092b30cb0~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_750,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Building a home involves 1) a lot to build on; and 2) a homebuilder to build on the lot.</p>

<p>A lot, meaning cleared land or land with teardown structures, is going to cost $20 to $25 per square foot in the East End and Near Northside. 5,000 square foot lots are the norm, meaning land cost ranges from $100,000 to $125,000.</p>

<p>As far as homebuilders, you have a range of options. Middle of the road pricing is $120 per square foot for these neighborhoods. This is an all-in price, including plans, permits and construction costs.</p>

<p>In total, building a new home on a 5,000 square foot lot with 3 bedrooms, 2 baths will cost a homebuyer $322,000 to $365,000 for an 1,850 to 2,000 square foot home with contemporary, above average finishes.</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/9e335e_6c444fc3dd6949f085238f017fa1262b~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_956,h_238,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>A quick search on real estate websites, like HAR.com, for new homes in these market areas will highlight the value of building, where similar homes are fetching sales prices in the high $300,000s and low $400,000s.</p><hr><h2><strong>The math is straightforward, but how do homebuyers finance the construction of a new home?</strong></h2><p>N.B. – Banks are offering a range of financing options for homebuyers in Houston who want to build their homes. Just like a traditional mortgage, banks are offering loan products to cover the entire process of building a new home. So, in a single loan, homebuyers are able to purchase a lot and pay for the cost of construction. These loans automatically convert to 30-year mortgages without having to go through a costly refinance process.</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/11062b_9759fea5d9b14ae2a3201c6c8d7156c2~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Banks are looking at the same economics that I highlighted in my example and using pre-construction appraisals to validate the math that I walked through. Banks are in the business of lending money to markets that are predictable and have collateral to cover the money they lend out. So lending homebuyers $325,000 to build a home in Houston’s stable economy that is certified with an appraisal of $375,000 is good business and relatively low risk for banks.</p>

<p>And for homebuyers, building a home that includes an equity surplus above the cost to build is a fantastic investment.</p><hr><h2><strong>What is the advantage of building a new home vs. buying a ready-built home?</strong></h2><p>N.B. – First, you get to choose what you want in a home. When looking at ready-built homes, even new ones, you have to hope that you can find one that includes most of the things you want in a home. But ultimately, you end up settling for a home that has less than what you are looking for. </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/58a5eae4c299257d936b72e59167c178.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>When building a home, you decide what is included and what is left out. Want a larger family room? Higher ceilings? More cabinets in the kitchen? More storage space? Less grass to maintain? A gravel driveway? Specific fixtures? Flooring selections? Wall colors? You provide input into every element of your new home design.</p>

<p>Second, purchasing a new home is like purchasing a new car. A new car comes with a warranty and an initial maintenance agreement. If your new car has a problem, you take it to the dealership for a no-cost repair. When your new car needs its first oil change, it’s covered and performed by the dealership’s certified mechanics at no-cost. The same is true for a newly built home.</p>

<p>By law, newly built homes must be warrantied by the homebuilder. Typically, you will have a 1-year workmanship and materials warranty covering everything from paint touch ups, re-caulking, settling cracks and issues that arise in your first year. Then there is a 2-year warranty that covers your mechanical systems, including hot water, air conditioning, heating, plumbing and electrical systems. And, finally, a 10-year structural warranty covers the load-bearing elements of your home, such as the foundation, footings, floor framing, walls and partitions, roof framing, beams, headers and so forth.</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/22da903611924c41a0a1be1d3da3d857.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>The breadth of coverage and responsiveness associated with new home warranties simply does not exist for used homes. If there is a problem in your used home, you, the homebuyer, have to coordinate and pay for the fix yourself. If you are lucky, your used home came with a 1-year home warranty policy serviced by a third party. However, these policies tend to operate more like an insurance claim service with a gatekeeper that limits the fixes they perform and with longer wait times. In short, the quality of service between new and used home warranties simply does not compare.</p><hr><h2><strong>How does CRV Homes work with homebuyers who want to build a new home?</strong></h2><p>N.B. – CRV Homes is one-stop shop for homebuyers in Houston who want to build a new home. Our end-to-end homebuilding solution is 100% all-inclusive: finding a lot, demolishing existing structures, designing floor plans, acquiring building permits, performing construction activities, and servicing warranties. For a single per square foot price, CRV Homes will take care of every component to building a home. This turnkey service is a unique, one-of-a-kind solution in the Houston market.</p>

<p>If you want additional information on our service offerings, give us a call at 888.993.7871 or come visit our website at www.BuildinHouston.com, where you can chat live with a professional from our CRV Homes team until 12AM daily. It would be our pleasure to answer your new home building questions.</p><hr>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>